

Julio Cesar Ramirez Paredes

Profile

Bachelor of civil engineering, expert in engineering solutions for fluid mechanics and computational fluid dynamics in challenging problems.

Interest in fluid mechanics and programming languages.

Outstanding learning capacity, motivation to continue learning and orientation to achieve results in my career.

Social Network

Mz. C1 Lt. 26

- Mario Cavagnaro Bellavista, Callao
- **J** (+51) 939196012
- ✓ julio.ramirez@pucp.edu.pe
- in Linkedin
- Github
- Pucp
- **@** Website
- Resume

Languages

English Portuguese

Programming

C++
Fortran
Python

EDUCATION

Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú
Bachelor's Degree in Civil Engineering

San Miguel ,PE Jul 2019

WORK EXPERIENCE

• Hidro Mayu

Lambayeque, PE

 $Structural\ equipment\ installation\ assistant$

Mar 2023

• Mechanics of materials and structural analysis: Training to teachers about the equipment of the Universidad Nacional Pedro Ruiz Gallo's structural engineering laboratory

• Hidro Mayu

Huacho, PE

Hydraulic equipment maintenance support

Nov 2022

- Fluid mechanics and open channel hydraulics: Maintenance and training to teachers and students about the equipment of the Universidad Nacional José Faustino Sánchez Carrión's hydraulics laboratory
- Centro de Investigación y Tecnología del Agua Barranco, PE Research Assistant Sep 2019 - Nov 2021
 - **Urban air quality**: Numerical simulation of the navier equations for incompresible newtonian flow in air fluid in urban environments using Openfoam.
 - Dam break: Numerical modeling of the shallow water equation for incompresible newtonian flow in dam break escenarios using Telemac-2D.
- Universidad de Ingeniería y Tecnologia Teaching Assistant

Barranco, PE
Aug 2019 - Nov 2021

 \circ ${\bf Mathematics}$ ${\bf III}:$ Solid understanding of linear algebra and numerical

- methods.
- Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú San Miguel, PE

 Jefe de Práctica Mar 2019 Jun 2019
 - Open Channel Hydraulics: Solid understading of channel morphology, hydraulic engineering and sediment transport.
- MJ & Asociados Water Resources Consulting Lima, PE
 Practicing civil engineer Mar 2019 Jun 2019
 - **River flood**: Observation of flood zone in the Moquegua river under extreme flood condition to investigate the resilience of the infrastructure.

Courses

- Programming CFD OpenFOAM- CFD Direct 2021
- Fire modelling with OpenFOAM- OpenFOAM 2020
- OpenFOAM turbulence CFD Support 2019
- OpenFOAM advanced CFD Support 2019
- Open source hydraulics modelling of shallow water flow Universidad Nacional de Ingeniería National Hydraulics Laboratory 2018
- Autocad 2018 advanced Centro de Cómputo UNIMASTER 2018

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- Programming Languages: C++, Fortran, Python, R, Javascript, Bash y Lisp.
- Softwares: Hecras, Telemac, OpenFOAM, Qgis, Arcgis, Emacs, Pointwise, Tecplot, Blender, Autocad, Latex, Ubuntu, Git y Aws.
- Tiping: Typing speed of 65 wpm Monkeytype, Keybr.